Sirisha PV

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India



sirisha.samudrala15@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/samudralasirisha



9398991565



https://sirishasamudrala5.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Technical Lead with 6+ yrs of experience in full stack development with a strong record of building an efficient team. Proficient in handling architectural changes. Following Agile methodology and polishing code quality of the team. Empowering the team driven by the values of growth, diversity and balance.

My current responsibilities include: Team leadership, Technical(Software Architecture) design, Project management, Technical hiring, People Management. TestDriven Development, Code reviews, Up-skilling team, DB management, Sprint planning.

Experience



🚯 Technical Lead

HealthPlix

Aug 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months)

- Successfully initiated, designed and executing the core product revamp with cutting edge tech [Micro FrontEnds + Micro Services]
- Responsible for weekly releases, DB operation requests, Sprint planning, Resource management
- Successfully delivered new features to improve user experience and reduce the consultation time [OCR, prescription in SMS, Knowledge repo]
- Mentoring Engineering team to up-skill in Go, Python, Typescript, ORMs, micro-front-ends, storybooks UI, TailwindCSS, NodeJs
- Successfully designed, executed and delivered doctor referral program which increased lead generation & a multi platform desktop application to increase the throughput of users with limited internet facility
- Complete project ownership whilst handling the team of FE and BE engineers and devOps following Agile Methodologies
- Perform code reviews to improve code quality and logical thinking of team
- Organised team building activities and brown bag sessions to boost our work culture
- Crafted Internship programs
- Actively aided Technical Hiring

Senior Software Engineer

Justdial

May 2021 - Aug 2021 (4 months)

- Developed POCs in Next.js, Leaflet.js & MongoDB
- Worked in Hotels vertical



Senior Software Engineer II

HashedIn by Deloitte

May 2019 - May 2021 (2 years 1 month)

- Grabbed the onsite work opportunity with one of our biggest client's Honeywell, migrated Safety Suite Product code from React15 to React16
- Built a mobile application [in React Native, NodeJs, Loopback3 & PostgreSQL], provided a plugin [in .NetCore] for our client Adecco
- Built a multi-tenant web application [in Python, Okta (SSO), Casbin, FastAPI, React.js, TypeScript.js, GMaps] for our Australian client Render Networks
- Actively aided technical hiring, team bonding activities and in-house training program called HashedIn university to train and mentor newly onboarded & junior developers

Software Engineer

Inspirisys Solutions Limited (a CAC Holdings Group Company)

Dec 2018 - Feb 2019 (3 months)

- Independently built a chatbot management dashboard [in React.js, NodeJs, Python & PostgreSQL, GraphQL, MongoDB to feed/train a chatbot]
- Improved the dialog flow functionality of chatbot widget
- Actively aided Technical Hiring

Application Developer

Divum Corporate Services Pvt Ltd

Jun 2018 - Oct 2018 (5 months)

- Analysed different cloud technologies [GCP, AWS, Oracle and SAP] to suggest right one based on client's requirements
- Lead a team of two on building BE service [in Flask(Python)] for a multi-tenant SASS product
- Developed POCs on SAP IoT that connects SAPUI5 to HANA, cross platform integration [Magento with Google datastore]
- Contributed in building an open source library to generate jsonLD using Python (for param.io)

Full Stack Developer

GoBumpr-myTVS

Dec 2016 - May 2018 (1 year 6 months)

- Independently developed company's first internal CRM [in core PHP7, Javascript & MySQLi, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Ajax] massively moved the customer engagement activities from excel sheets to dynamic website thus saved 60% of time for customer support team & BDMs
- Built Admin panels to monitor conversion rate using Heat-maps, and other metrics
- Built complementary static websites for the garage partners in an interactive way
- Written RESTFul APIs [in GoLang] for Axle App
- Actively aided in hiring interns- Built complementary static websites for the garage partners in an interactive way
- Written RESTFul APIs [in GoLang] for Axle App
- Actively aided in hiring interns

Education

International School of Engineering (INSOFE)

PG, Data science

2019 - 2019

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), computer science and engineering 2012 - 2016

- *Hosted many extra curricular activities and co curricular activities. *Topper of cse branch.
- *Participated in workshops(android, ethical hacking).
- *Presented papers(in data mining ,introduction to android operating system ,mobile cloning).

Licenses & Certifications



AWS Technical Professional - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Certified Data Scientist - Carnegie Mellon University

Udemy certified GoLang Developer - Udemy UC-8be30d0a-93c8-4d97-b6aa-5c59c0e05a9f

Udemy certified gRPC [Golang| developer - Udemy UC-cca7b339-26f2-4295-a1ad-6a8271a798e5

Skills

Non-Functional Requirements • Engineering Management • Team Leadership • Code Review • Agile Methodologies • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Software Architecture • Technical Presentations • Microservices • Debugging